<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/Impossible-Maps-Blog%22%22/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/Impossible-Maps-Blog%22%22/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-01-29T22:26:32-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Impossible-Maps-Blog%22%22/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Impossible Maps Independent Study</title><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title type="html">Assignment Week-1</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Impossible-Maps-Blog%22%22/assignment/2019/01/27/Assignment1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Assignment Week-1" /><published>2019-01-27T20:09:18-05:00</published><updated>2019-01-27T20:09:18-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Impossible-Maps-Blog%22%22/assignment/2019/01/27/Assignment1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Impossible-Maps-Blog%22%22/assignment/2019/01/27/Assignment1.html"></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Reflection Week-1</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Impossible-Maps-Blog%22%22/reflections/2019/01/27/welcome-to-jekyll.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Reflection Week-1" /><published>2019-01-27T20:09:18-05:00</published><updated>2019-01-27T20:09:18-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Impossible-Maps-Blog%22%22/reflections/2019/01/27/welcome-to-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Impossible-Maps-Blog%22%22/reflections/2019/01/27/welcome-to-jekyll.html">&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed reading Experimental Geography. I had never before considered the role of cartography in imperial conquest, that, as the the authors puts it, “if new territories were to be controlled they had to be mapped”. I wonder to what magnitude those effects translate to modern day imperial regimes and their use of mapping tools. Are the effects more pronounced as not only is there more data but also the data is now more exact? On the other hand, mapping data is no longer a heavily guarded secret that only a few can access, even a small rebel group planning an attack on a government territory can study the territory using Google maps and use that information to an advantage. Does this democratization of access mean that cartography’s usefulness for imperialistic regimes is subsiding? I also found the later part of the reading on “producing space” and viewing space not as an inert object to be studied but as something that is void without human action very interesting, especially in how that relates to political thought, that “there can be no outside of politics because there can be no ‘outside’ to the production of space”. I like how that philosophical view renders the conception of apoliticality irrelevant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first two readings took me longer to understand and process. Borges’s tale, picturing the crumbling of the empire through the crumbling of a tangible object, a 1:1  map, was comical, and I love how it reduced the empire to a piece of paper that can be shred and discarded, but I wonder if there is some broader commentary on the empire that the author was hinting at, or if I am missing out on some idea behind the nature of science or geography that the author communicated through the tale. To understand the piece by Bauldirllard, I had to do some additional reading to understand what he means by the “Simularca”. His conception that simulations create reality, that maps don’t “precede the territory”, that the map in Borges tale is not a mirror but a being in itself, seems detached, in the sense, that it almost rejects all materialistic conceptions of the world, which I had trouble wrapping my head around.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I enjoyed reading Experimental Geography. I had never before considered the role of cartography in imperial conquest, that, as the the authors puts it, “if new territories were to be controlled they had to be mapped”. I wonder to what magnitude those effects translate to modern day imperial regimes and their use of mapping tools. Are the effects more pronounced as not only is there more data but also the data is now more exact? On the other hand, mapping data is no longer a heavily guarded secret that only a few can access, even a small rebel group planning an attack on a government territory can study the territory using Google maps and use that information to an advantage. Does this democratization of access mean that cartography’s usefulness for imperialistic regimes is subsiding? I also found the later part of the reading on “producing space” and viewing space not as an inert object to be studied but as something that is void without human action very interesting, especially in how that relates to political thought, that “there can be no outside of politics because there can be no ‘outside’ to the production of space”. I like how that philosophical view renders the conception of apoliticality irrelevant.</summary></entry></feed>